Guide to the Felix Adler Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Classified Papers
  - Subseries II.2. General Classification (200)
    - 214 Jewish Subjects
      - Jewish View of Jesus (Enelow) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Title of Jews ·to Homeland in Palestine (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - In rebus Judaieis (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - The Palestine Report (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - History of Israel (Wellhausen) (2) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Condition of the Jews in Russia (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Confirmation address (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - Jewish marriage (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - The Hagada (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - History of the religious school of the Temple Emanuel (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - Address delivered at the Hebrew Orphan Asylum, 1869 December 11 (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - Address delivered at the Hebrew Orphan Asylum, 1869 November 20 (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - Jewish and xtn ideals (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Prayers of Israel (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Old Testament and New Testament (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - A variety of Zionism (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Valid Differences - Judaism and Christianity (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Points in the Development of Jewish Religion (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Maimonides (2) (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - The Heroes of "Legalism" (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - The Jewish People in the time of Christ (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Jewish Religion (Resurrection) (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Dubner – History of the Jews in Russia dn Poland (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - "Ethical Wills" (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Zionism - Jastrow (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Old and N.T. and the Jewish Religion (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - The Passover (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - The Day of Atonement (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Interview with Hebrew Students (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Montefiore Hebrew religion (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - The Judaism of the future (Adler, 1873) (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - The main affirmations [of Hebraic prophecy] (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Zionist and assimilationist (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - The Jewish Service (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Zionist, Assimilationist, and Ethical Point of view (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - The Jewish Question (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Hebrew Religion (3) (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Keynote of Hebrew Religion and Xtnty (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Note son Hebrew Monotheism (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Philo (3) (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Psychological Note on the Anti-Semitic Movement (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Israel and its Culture (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Genius of Judaism (2) (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - The legacy of Israel [1932-3] (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - History of the Marranos (C. Roth) (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Fragments of a Samaritan Targum (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Place of the Jew in Western civilization (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - The Temple of Jerusalem (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Concerning the perpetuation of the Jewish race (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Moore’s Judaism (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Abstract of Moral Code in the Pentateuch (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Mendelssohn (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Points in Jewish History (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Birth of Personality among the Hebrews (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Remarks on the Septuagint (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - The Cabala (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Nachmanides (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Religion of Israel (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - 215 Poets and Poetry
      - Schiller on the sublime (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Milton- Paradise Lost (2) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Dorothy Wordsworth (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Schiller (Folder 1)
        - The Aesthetic Education of Man (Box 47, Folder 1)
        - Religion (Box 47, Folder 1)
        - Naïve and Sentimental Poets (Box 47, Folder 1)
        - Essay on Grace and Dignity (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Milton (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Religion is Poetry – Poetic Genius and Religious Genius (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Wordsworth – Poet’s Epitaph – Prefaces (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - The Poet’s Life and Works (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Keats’ Letters (3) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Religious Poetry (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Poetry (Enc. Brit) (2) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Religious Poetry – The Ramayan (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Selective Principle in Dramatic Art (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Chanson de Roland (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Place of the Drama in Religious Life (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - 215.01 Poets and Poetry--Dante
      - Of sin and expiation (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Purgatory (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - The New Life (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Divine Commedia (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Monarchy (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Dante’s Relation to Nature (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Spiritual Message of (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Notes for the Address on Dante's Beatrice (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - 215.02 Poets and Poetry--Shakespeare
      - Shakespeariana (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - King Lear (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Notes on King Lear (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - “Hamlet” and “King Lear” (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - “Richard III” (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - “Hamlet” (2) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - “Cymbeline” (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - “The Tempest” (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Bradley's Essays on Shakespearean Tragedy (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Differences between My Interpretation and Werder's (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - The Passing Day (Hamlet) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Shakespeare's Macbeth (2) (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - Notes on Macbeth (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - Shakespeare's Midsummer night's dream (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - Timon of Athens (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - Stevenson on the Gentleman (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - The Shakespearean Plays (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - Macbeth (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - “All’s Well that Ends Well” (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - “The Merchant of Venice” (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - Marriage in Shakespeare’s Plays (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - “As You Like It” (Box 47, Folder 1a)
      - Hamlet (Box 47, Folder 1b)
    - 215.03 Poets and Poetry--Goethe (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - 216 Jottings (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
    - 216.01 Jottings--Reflections (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
    - 217 Books (Notes) Miscellaneous
      - Lewissohn- Upstream (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Bossuet (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Calderon- Life a Dream (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Villey – Le Monde des Aveugles (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Warner – Essays, in the Wilderness (2) (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Daughter of the Samurai (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Stevenson – Letters, Pulvis et Umbra (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Swift – Tale of a Tub (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Hauf – Stories (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Maurcis – Ariel (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Ewald – Die Wiedergeburt des Geistes (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Kipling – the Seven Seas (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Pear – 46 Years in Constantinople (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Bernstorff – My 3 years in America (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Eliot (George) – Middlemarch (2), Daniel Deronda, Romola (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Randall – The Western Mind (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Lippman – Preface to Politics (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Mirros of Downing St. (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Wallas, G. – The Great Society – Human Nature in Politics (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Brailsford – War of Steel and Cold (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Robinson – Mind in the Making (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Maeterlinck – Wisdom and Destiny (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Hayes – My Leper Friends (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Guyau – note (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Donne, “Blathanatos” (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - Bacon, Essay on truth (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Bacon, Eidola tribiis (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Bacon's essays (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Barras, "The spiritual families of France" (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Bourget, "Nos actes nous suivent" (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Browne, Christian morals (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Calvin's Institutes (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Carnegie Foundation Report on public school education (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Cervantes, "Don Quixote" (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Coleridge, Biographia literaria (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Cumberland, Set down in malice (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Bacon - Advancement of Learning (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Bacon – Essays (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Balfour - Foundations of Belief (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Berkeley (3) (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Borah (Article in Times) (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Burgess - Political Science (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Calhoun - Disquisition on Government (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Cole - World of Labor (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Croly - Progressive Democracy (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - [Edwards] The colonial mind (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - [Edwards] Second volume of Paddington (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Friedel, Kulturgeschichte der Neuzeit (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Fuller, Worthies of England (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Grotius, De Jure Belli et Pacis (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Hartmann's Ethics (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Hawthorne, Minister's black veil (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Ireland, Life of Pulitzer (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Lessing, Nathan the wise (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Lowie's Primitive society (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Marx, Das Kapital (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Grotius (Neumann's notes) (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Duncan- Story of Metlakantle (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Hallam - Grotius (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Hobjouse - Morals in Evolution (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - King-Psychology of Child Development (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - McGiffert - God of Early Christians (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - McKechnie-The State and the Individual (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Marco Polo (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Mezes - Ethics (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Paley-Moral Philosophy (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Pater, Marius the Epicurean (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Pritchett's Report on education (Adler) (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Schneider, Making the Fascist state (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Siegfried, Les etats unis (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Perry - The New Realism (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Pritchett-Report on Education (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Riehl (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Seth-Study or Ethical Principles (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Shaftesbury-Inquiry concerning virtue and merit (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Smith (Kemp) – Paper on Renaissance (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Steiner (Rudo1ph)-The Three Commonwealths (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Strong- Why the Mind has a Body (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Uilamuno (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Thomasius (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Thring (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Volkmann-Psychology (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Wallas (Graham)-Human Nature in Politics (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Ward -·Naturalism and Agnosticism (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Wolf (Christian)-Chapter in Bluntschli (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Bodin (Janet’s Chapter) (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Zwingli (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - 217.01 Books--Coit
      - Coit, National idealism (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Ethical Lecturers' Fund Com., Stanton Coit’s statement (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Certain Portraits (Stanton Coit) (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - The Two Steps Proposed by Coit (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Coit (Folder 1)
        - The Soul of America (Box 48, Folder 1)
        - The Dynamics of Democracy (Box 48, Folder 1)
        - Ethical Movement (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - 218 Morality and Ethics
      - Individual Ethics
        - Fitting one's back to the burden (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Vital problems of today (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Ethical reinterpretations (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Psychological note on giving (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Congeniality (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Principles of liberty (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Situations to test ethical principles (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - The Mortal Sins (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Work and Play (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Self-Discipline (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Weakness of the Will (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - The Broken Will (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Liberty and Control (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Remuneration (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Wagner on Motives (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Maurice’s Consciences (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Grim on Old Age (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - The notion of Ripeness (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Paths of Personal Peace (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Critical Periods of Life (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Frustration (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Freedom and Wisdom (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Falsehood (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Major Interests and Maximum Interests (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Vital Problems (2) (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Ethico Religious Topics
        - Principles of ethics and religion (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - Ethical hygiene (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - The Ethical Problem (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - Man a Product of Nature (2) (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - Is the Foundation of “Hope” sound (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - The Greater and the Lesser Evil (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - The Bruising Effect of sensitiveness to the world (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - Simple and Complex Ethical Tasks (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - The Task of Humanity (2) (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - Facing Life as it is (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - Systems of Self-Discipline (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - An Ideal Type; and Vital Problems (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Morality (Public and Private)
        - Group morality in its relation to freedom (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Moral experiences (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Discord between moral and physical order (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Difference between the natural law & a moral law (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Additional remarks (cave man vs. modern man) (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Moral askesis (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Articles on Moral problems (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Man to man morality and morality of Nations (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Philistine Morality (2) (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Motive Power in the Moral Life (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Origin and Development of Moral Ideas (Westermarck) (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Public and Private morality (3) (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Immoralism and Its Roots (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Right and Wrong Acts (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - The New Conscience (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Ethical Definitions
        - Ethical Irony (2) (Box 49, Folder 4)
        - Man vs. the Gentleman (Box 49, Folder 4)
        - The Idea of Justice (2) (Box 49, Folder 4)
        - A Definition of Wisdom (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Ethics--Miscellaneous
        - Will to be1ieve &ethical ground of belief (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Medical ethics (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Ethical approach to reality (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Ethical view of 1ife (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Principles and precepts (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Source of power- in Ethical movement (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Metaphysical character of ethical ideal (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Through Darkness to Light (2) (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Freedom within the Limits (2) (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Impending Changes (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Poetry of an Office Building (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Visiting the Sick (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Claim of aged to reverence (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Effects of New View on Immortality and Sin (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Constructive Principle of Status Relations (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Ethical Imagination (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Four cardinal virtues (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Sacraments of the Ethical 1ife (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Vicarious punishment (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Notes on character (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Notes on the duty of veracity (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Self-sacrifice (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - The Two Voices (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Sequence of Virtues (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Loyalty (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Truth Telling (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Statement of way of Living (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Special Moral Defects (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Duties (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Repentance (Von Hartmann) (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Character (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Is Cynical View of Human Nature Warranted? (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - The Cardinal Virtues (2) (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Temperance-Sunday Opening of Saloons (2) (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Substitutes for the Saloon (Box 49, Folder 5a)
        - Additional on punishment (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - Our duties to others (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - Chief classes of duties (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - Conflict of duties (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - The idea of truthfulness· (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - Truth and authorship (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - Punishment of Children (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - Notes on the Family (Lippert) (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - New View of Childhood (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - Truthfulness (2) (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - Secular Morality (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - Traditional Morality (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - Happiness and Morality (Sanders) (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - Duties (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - Hill - The significance of coercion (Box 49, Folder 5b)
        - Presenting the task of humanity (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Man as the subject of duty (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Classification of duties (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Happiness (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Shadow of sin (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Absolute values (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - What is vanity? (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Pleasure (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Truthfulness and Honesty (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Pity and Terror (2) (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Sin end Society (Ross) (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Unity of Mankind (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - A World Conscience and History of Desire for Happiness (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Love your enemies (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Reverence (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Dignity (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Piety (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Conscience (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Duties (Box 49, Folder 5c)
        - Clarification of the Ethical Ideal (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - The Right to Live and the Duty of Living (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - The Meaning of Evil (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - Part Which the Ideal Plays in the Actual' Life of Beeple (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - Ethical reinterpretations (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - The psychology of gratitude (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - The concept of honor (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - Ethical Idea in the Marketplace (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - Eternal Values (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - True Morality Mocks at Morality (Pascal) (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - 2 Levels of Ethical Life (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - Middle Class Morality in Light of War (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - Applicability of Moral Law (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - Is it Possible to do right? (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - The Problem of Evil (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - Gratitude (HYD) (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - Effect of large ideas in hardening Human nature (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - A New commandment (Box 49, Folder 5d)
        - Irrationalism (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Perfection vs. ens perfectissimum (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Analysis of self-denial and self-sacrifice (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - The essential self (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Admiration (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - One who has lived the life of wealthy (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Humanism (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Do the means justify the end? (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Detachment (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Society and Solitude (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Civilization (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Plan of Ethical Living (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - A Moral Question (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Ethics of Equality (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Ethik – Lazarus (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Prayer (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Self-Transformation as the West (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Self-sacrifice (vicarious) (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Self-denial (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Self-discipline (2) (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Self-knowledge (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Minor Morals (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Applause (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Chivalry (Box 49, Folder 5e)
        - Definitions (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Good as Foe of Better (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - False Ethics in discussion of War (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Peace at center of storm (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Work of the Imagination on character (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Egocentrism, Natural Liberty, 5 rules (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Reconciling oneself to hardships (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Qualities by which mankind will be redeemed (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Weakness as Source of Badness (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Beauty and Ugliness 0f Actions (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Obstacles designed to Provoke Power (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Confession (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Survey started by Tennyson's line (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Friendship (2) (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Principles of Ethics (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - The Logic of Ethics (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Data of Ethics (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Foundation of Ethics (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - The One Thing in Life That· Matters (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Ethical realism - definition (Box 49, Folder 5f)
        - Friendship (notes) (Box 49, Folder 5f)
    - 218.01 Morality and Ethics--Personal Relations
      - Treatment of Enemies (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Responsibility (3) (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Problems of the Personal Life (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Living and Dying in others (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Change in in Human Relations (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - New Way of Attacking the Social Problem (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Note – Friendship – Way of Living (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Hate – Filial Piety (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Prejudice (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Humility (2) (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Additional Notes on Prejudice (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Uncongenial Natures in Close Connection (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - The Enemies by Which I Am Surrounded (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - The crises of life (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - How to behave towards' the unjust (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - The general conception of life (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Symbolic aspect of human relationships (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Relation of diversity to unity (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Problem of unity in diversity (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Incompatibility in persona1 relations (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - 218.02 Morality and Ethics--Death, Suicide, Consolations, Immortality
      - Is the voluntary ending of one's life ever permissible (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Notes on immortality (2) (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Death and immortality (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - The desire for immortality (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Belief in immortality (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Syllabus - on suicide (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Notes on suicide (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Notes for a paper on suicide (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Hume on suicide (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - A book of consolations (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - A vision of the night (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Remarks on transposition (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Individual salvation (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - At the terminus (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Contemplation of death (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Immortality (3) (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Suicide (2) (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Cremation (Box 49, Folder 1)